Finding Aid for the Charles W. Warterfield Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Charles W. Warterfield Collection
1949-1952
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0491
.42 linear_feet
Biography/History
Charles W. Warterfield (1926-1988) received a Bachelor of Arts Degree from Vanderbilt University in 1950. He later became Chairman of the Historical Commission, designed the General Jackson Showboat for Opryland, served on the planning team for the Bicentennial Mall, and co-authored several books about Nashville. Other photograph collections by Charles W. Warterfield, which relate to architecture in Nashville, may be found at the Tennessee State Library and Archives (copy attached), and the Nashville Public Library [Nashville Room]
Scope and Contents
This .42 linear feet collection contains a total of 254 images. There are 142 [8x10] black and white images of student activities from the 1949-1950 academic year. There are 16 [8x10] numbered contact sheets of campus buildings, all identified, for a total of 65 images. And, there are four oversized contact sheets [10x12] of fraternity houses, reunion 1950, and commencement 1952, unidentified, for a total of 47 images. The images are arranged by subject, sleeved, placed in file folders, and stored in one manuscript box. These images have been indexed into a database.
- Subjects (142 images) (Box 1)
  - All-Star Game, 1949-1950; 5
  - Alumni Hall Cafeteria – ‘The Stupid’, 1949; 1
  - Athletics – Men – Football – circa, 1949; 1
  - Board of Trust, 1949-1950; 1
  - Bookstore (barracks), 1949-1950; 3
    - [Lackey twins identified in one]
  - Campus Scenes, 3
    - [Bill Price, 3rd from left], circa, 1949
    - circa, 1949
    - Alumni Terrace, n.d
  - Car, 1949-1950; 1
  - Christmas Banquet, 1949-1950; 1
  - Commencement, 1950; 1
  - Commencement, 1951; 1
  - Dances
    - Coed Ball – King Rex, 1949-1950; 1
    - Junior Prom, 1949-1950; 1
      - (Owen Bradley Band)
    - Kappa Delta Dance, n.d; 2
    - Miami Triad, 1949-1950; 3
    - Sigma Chi Dance – Maxwell House, 1949-1950; 2
    - Sigma Chi Harvest Ball, 1949; 1
    - Sorority Tea Dance, n.d; 2
    - Unidentified, 3
  - Derby Day – Sigma Chi, 1949; 1
    - [Jimmy Diffee, Mernie Hodge]
  - Derby Day – Sigma Chi, 1950; 4
    - [Manie ‘Rip’ Reynolds and Sally Brad Richardson]
  - Fine Arts – circa [Mary Louise Manlove Rutherford], 1950; 1
  - Freshman Party, 1950; 2
    - [Nancy White, Nancy Minnick, unidentified] [Nancy White, Nancy Minnick, unidentified – center rear, Kathryn Wallston]
  - Homecoming – Phi House, 1949-1950; 1
  - Homecoming – Theta House circa, 1949; 1
  - Homecoming Parade, 1949; 7
  - Intramural – Men – Basketball, n.d; 3
  - Intramural – Men – Swimming, 1949; 4
  - Intramural – Men – Track, 1949-1950; 1
  - Intramural – Men – Volleyball, 1949; 2
  - Intramural – Women – Basketball, n.d; 6
  - Kirkland Hall, 1950; 4
  - Library – JUL, 1949-1950; 2
  - Neely Auditorium, 1949-1950; 7
    - (interior and exterior)
  - Outing – Unidentified, 8
  - Pep Rally, 1949-1950; 1
  - Pep Rally – Church Street, 1949-1950; 5
  - Pep Rally – Hermitage Hotel, 1949-1950; 7
  - Pep Rally – Pajama Parade, 1949-1950; 1
  - Pep Rally – War Memorial Steps, 1949-1950; 1
  - Phi House – Chef, 1949; 1
    - [Walter Whitaker]
  - Phi House – Mother’s Tea, May 1949; 1
    - [Walter Whitaker]
  - Phi House – Students, 1949; 1
    - [Bill Kimbrough, Bob Tigert]
  - Picnic – Freshman, 1949-1950; 3
  - Registration, 1949-1950; 2
  - Reunions, 1950; 5
  - Reunions, 1952; 8
  - ROTC – Navy, 1949-1950; 3
  - SCA – Meetings, 1950; 3
    - [Dr. Walter Stoves]
    - [Mrs. Bransford in background]
    - [Lackey, Dr. Walter Stove, Vernon Sharp, Sam West, unidentified]
  - SCA – Retreat, 1949; 2
  - Student Activities – Bridge, 1949-1950; 1
  - Student Activities – Pool, 1949-1950; 1
  - Stunt Night, 1949-1950; 1
  - Stuart, Jesse, 1949-1950; 1
  - Swimming Party, May 1950; Phi Rush 3
- Contact Sheets (65 images) (Box 1)
  - Sheet #1 – 4 images
    - Kirkland Hall
    - JUL
    - Calhoun Hall
    - Garland Hall
  - Sheet #2 – 4 images
    - Kirkland Hall
    - Neely
    - Hospital (2)
  - Sheet #3 – 4 images
    - McT (2)
    - Cole & Tolman
    - Calhoun
  - Sheet #4 – 2 images
    - JUL
    - Garland Hall
  - Sheet #5 – 4 images
    - JUL (3)
    - Furman Hall
  - Sheet #6 – 4 images
    - McT
    - Kirkland Hall
    - Calhoun Hall
    - Unidentified
  - Sheet #7 – 4 images
    - JUL (2)
    - Cole
    - Unidentified Construction
  - Sheet #8 – 4 images
    - Kirkland hall
    - JUL
    - Neely
    - Central
  - Sheet #9 – 4 images
    - Buttrick – Old Bookstore
    - Alumnus
    - Kissam Hall
    - Furman Hall
  - Sheet #10 – 4 images
    - Kissam Hall (old)
    - Old Central Porch
    - JUL
    - Dorm?
  - Sheet #11 – 4 images
    - Alumni Hall
    - Cole Dorm
    - Stadium (2)
  - Sheet #12 – 4 images
    - Construction – Engineering (4)
  - Sheet #13 – 4 images
    - Alumni Hall
    - Kirkland Hall (3)
  - Sheet #14 – 4 images
    - Construction – Engineering (3)
    - Hospital
  - Sheet #15 – 9 images
    - Kirkland Hall (4)
    - Buttrick Hall
    - Furman Hall
    - Alumnus
    - Commodore Statue
    - Mechanical Engineering
    - JUL
    - Hospital
    - Calhoun
  - Sheet #16 – 2 images
    - Kirkland Hall (2)
- Contact Sheets - Oversized (47 images) (Box 1)
  - Sheet #17 – 6 images
    - Fraternity Houses, 1950
  - Sheet #18 – 5 images
    - Fraternity Houses, 1950
  - Sheet #19 – 6 images
    - Fraternity Houses, 1950 (3)
    - Reunion, 1950 (3)
  - Sheet #20– 30 images
    - Commencement, June 1952